精 灵 旅 社 2
恭祝新婚 梅维丝和强纳
一 年 后
坚持住 宝贝
产房
黑暗森林 市政公园 和自行车道
右转
丹尼斯五岁生日派对
- 翻译：JOPHY ALEX YOU 九月 恶熏 -
- 校对：JOPHY 总监：JOPHY -
- 特效：BUNNY 压制：侠肠无医 -
- SSK字幕组译制 -
- 仅供学习，勿用于商，转载请注明出处，版权归片方所有 -
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome! Welcome!
恭喜恭喜啊 德古拉
Congrats, Drac.
我的天啊 大家都来了
Holy smokes, everybody's here.
洛克伦夫妇 新郎的父母亲和家人到场
Mr. And Mrs. Loughran, the parents of the groom, and family.
妈妈爸爸 强纳森
Mom and Dad! Johnny!
你们居然都来了
I can't believe you're all here.
哦 美美美
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah!
唷 我的女伴多美啊
Yo, how hot is my date?
美呆了 哇哦
So hot. Wow.
那你说我的女伴有多美
How 'bout how hot mine is?
你有个女伴
You got a date?
对 她也是隐形的 所以你们看不见她
Yeah. She's invisible. That's why you can't see her.
哦 是啊 来自加拿大的那位吗
Oh, right. This is the one from "Canada"?
婚礼开始了
Wedding's starting.
太棒了
Great.
对 说得太对了 马蒂
True. So true, Marty.
好贴心啊
Aw. How sweet.
哦 天啊 瞧瞧你
Oh, my. Look at you.
哦 天啊
Oh, my gosh.
这是你想要的吗 我的小蜜糖
Is it everything you wanted, my little poisonberry?
是的 爸爸
Oh, it is, Daddy.
只不过 弗拉德爷爷怎么没来
Except where's Grandpa Vlad?
宝贝 你爷爷不会同意这事的
Honey, your gramps would not have been cool with this.
他相当老派
He's old-school.
我们怎么知道 如果他能见见强尼
How do we know? If he could just meet Johnny...
他会吃了他的
He would have eaten him.
他可不想你酷爸爸我这么开明
He's not as enlightened as your hip Daddy.
所以 你真的可以接受他不是个怪物吗
So, you're really okay with him not being a monster?
人也好 怪物也罢 独角兽都行 只要你幸福就好
Human, monster, unicorn, as long as you're happy.
谢谢 爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
#你一直都是我的月光#
# And you'll always be my moonlight #
#但如今你乘着爱的翅膀飞翔#
# But now on wings of love you soar #
#如今你是强尼的新娘#
# Now that you're Johnny's girl #
#强尼的新娘#
# Johnny's girl #
#但你也是爹地的宝贝#
# And kind of Daddy's, too #
#你妈妈会很高兴#
# Your mom would be so happy #
#因为她一直知道#
# 'Cause she always knew #
#是爱让你如此美好#
# Love is making room for all the best in you #
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Dad.
哦 嘿 你们好
Oh, hey, guys!
陶德 休息一下
Todd, take a break.
有什么事情
So, what's up?
梅维斯在想你要不要出去飞一下
Mavis was wondering if maybe you wanted to go for a fly.
我们从不干那事 有什么特别的原因吗
Oh. We haven't done that in forever. Any special reason?
完全没有特别原因
No special reason at all.
对吧 梅维
Right, Mavey?
他这是什么毛病
What's his deal?
他傻了
He's silly.
只是夜色很美 还有
It's just a beautiful night, and...
但是 如果你不想去的话
Well, if you don't want to...
不 不 开什么玩笑
No, no! Are you kidding?
只要能跟你出去飞 要我吃一桶大蒜都行
I would eat a bucket of garlic to fly with you.
宝贝 看看那些软蓬蓬的云朵
Oh, honey, look at those fluffy clouds.
还记得你小的时候我们都玩什么吗
Remember what we played when you were little?
还记得捉迷藏吗
Hide and Go Seek Sharp Objects?
好啊 跟往常一样的捉迷藏
Okay. Regular Hide and Go Seek.
你在哪里
Where are you?
我的蝙蝠小宝贝
Honeybat!
梅维
Mavey!
我的蝙蝠小宝贝
Honeybat!
我要抓到你了
I'm gonna get you.
宝贝 你没事吧
Honey? Are you okay?
没事 只是怀了孕之后
Yes. It's just a little harder
我有点喘不过气
to catch my breath since I'm pregnant.
对啊 我想那会更加
Yes, well, I guess that would make it more...
什么
What?
我要当外公了
I'm gonna be a grandpa!
而我要做爸爸了
And I'm gonna be a dad!
你是爸爸的小公主 或儿子
# 'Cause you're Daddy's girl, or boy #
爸爸的小公主 或儿子
# Daddy's girl, or boy #
我又饿了 亲爱的
I'm hungry again, honey.
你能帮我拿点鱼冰淇淋吗
Can you get me some ice cream with anchovies?
不行 不行 不行 你不能像你的欲望低头
No, no, no. You mustn't give in to your cravings.
那对孩子不好
It's not good for the baby.
你得多吃点蜘蛛
You need to increase your spider intake,
那样他才能爬上天花顶
so he'll be able to climb ceilings properly.
还要吃大量的羊胆汁
And eat lots of sheep bile.
我爱你 爸爸 但我们都还不知道
I love you, Dad, but we don't even know
这孩子会不会是个吸血鬼
if the kid's gonna be a vampire.
如果这孩子是个人类 像强尼一样 我也会很激动
I'd be thrilled if the baby's human-y, just like Johnny.
人类 考虑到德古拉家族数千年来的基因遗传
Human-y. With thousands of years of Dracula genes.
那是不可能的
Not gonna happen.
只要宝宝健康就好
As long as the baby's healthy.
当然了 一个健康的小吸血鬼
Of course. A healthy little vampire.
或者人类
Or human.
是 一个能像蝙蝠那样飞的人类
Yes, a human who can fly as a bat.
来 喝点怪物肉丸汤
Here. Just have some monster ball soup.
这可是按你妈咪的食谱做的哦
It's your mommy's recipe.
谢谢你 爸爸
Thank you, Dad.
就跟我小的时候你做的一样 我的最爱
Just like you made it when I was a kid. My favorite.
抱歉
Sorry.
先生 只有孩子的父亲能进产房
Sir, only the father is allowed in the delivery room.
真的吗 好吧
Really? I mean, okay.
他是家人吧 我猜
He's the family, I guess.
快看 是个男孩 是个男孩
Oh, look! It's a boy! It's a boy!
德古拉血脉的延续
The Dracula bloodline carries on!
只要我在 没人能伤害你
No one will ever harm you as long as I'm here,
我的小魔童
my little devil dog.
爸爸 我能抱一下我的孩子吗
Dad, can I hold my baby?
如果我是你爸爸 我会说好
If I were Dad, I'd say yes.
但人家是弗朗辛护士哦
But I'm the nurse, Francine.
总之呢 给你抱啦
Here you go anyway.
对不起
My bad.
小丹尼斯一岁了
Little Dennis is a year old now. Wow!
很好 很好 很可爱的孩子
Nice. Yeah. Cute kid.
好了 该拆礼物了 小朋友们
Okay, time for presents, guys.
好的 咱们一起让这孩子嗨起来吧
All right! Let's do this boy up!
瞧瞧我给他带了什么东西
Check out what I got him. Bling!
哇哦 这受了诅咒的吗
Wow. Is it cursed?
超强诅咒 但只有好的咒
Super cursed. Only the best.
直接从墓穴里拿出来的
Straight from the crypt.
他刚刚开始走路 所以这项链对他来说可能有点重
He's just starting to walk, so maybe it's heavier than...
没事的 丹尼索维奇
Oh. You're okay, Denisovich.
他的名字是丹尼斯 以我父亲的名字命名的
His name is Dennis. Named after my father.
但那不是他的吸血鬼名字
It's not his vampire name.
我的小小丹尼索维奇 维索维奇
My little Denisovichy-Weesovichy.
哈哈 我们确定他是吸血鬼吗
Huh! Are we sure he's a vampire?
我的意思是 那也不是什么坏事
I mean, not that it's a bad thing,
但他不是得长出你们那样的尖牙还有苍白肤色吗？
but shouldn't he have fangs and that pasty skin you guys have?
实际上 得等到
Technically, you have
五岁时 尖牙才会长出来
until you're five to get your vampire fangs.
他会长尖牙的 他是德古拉家的孩子
Oh, he'll get his fangs. He's a Dracula.
他也有一半洛克伦家的血统
He's also half Loughran.
或许他离开这里到我们家乡去会更好
Maybe he'd be better off where we live.
那儿有更多的人类
There's more humans there.
什么 看看他和他的狼人小伙伴玩得多好
What? Look how well he's playing with the wolf pups.
我们准备了一份礼物 希望你们会喜欢
We have a present. I hope it's acceptable.
我的第一部斩首机
My First Guillotine.
非常具有教育意义 送得好 弗兰克
Very educational. Well played, Frank.
太棒了 谢谢你们 只是我们得把这东西做一下婴儿保护
It's great. Thank you. We just have to baby-proof that.
强尼 你知道你把橡胶防护套放哪里了吗
Johnny, do you know where you put the rubber guards?
给斩首机加婴儿保护套
Baby-proofing a guillotine?
那样才能把手指头切下来 那可是乐趣之一啊
So you cut your finger off. It's part of the fun.
她让我把整个旅馆都加了婴儿保护
She made me baby-proof the whole hotel.
有人过度保护了啊
Someone's overprotective.
强尼 快点过来
Johnny! Come quick!
怎么了 他没事吧
What's up? He's okay?
丹尼斯刚刚开口说话了
Dennis said his first word!
他说了吗
He did?
来 宝宝 再说一次
Come on, honey. Say it again.
给我血 血 血
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
我没说 给我血 血 血
I don't say, "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我们没说你说了啊
We didn't say you did.
那他从哪儿听到这话的
Then where did he get that?
给我血 血 血
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
这个嘛 可能你有时候有说吧
Well, maybe sometimes you say it.
我只有在反驳我没有说的时候才会说这话
I only say it when I say I don't say it!
给我血 血 血
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
好吧 小子 我们收到了 你可以说话了
Okay, kid. We get it. You can talk.
丹尼索维奇
Denisovich.
爸爸
Dad.
检查一下有没有蛀牙而已
Just checking for cavities.
给我血 血 血
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
原来是你
It was you!
哦 天啊 莱纳德
Oh, my goodness, Leonard.
如果你真的长得这么丑
If you really looked that hideous,
我觉得我没法跟你出去
I don't think I could hang out with you.
伙计们 现在是什么情况
Guys, what's the deal?
这是在开派对吗 快接电话
Is this a party? Pick up a phone.
我不管强尼是不是说这是一个很酷的应用软件
I don't care if Johnny said it's a "Cool app."
强尼才来这儿没多久
Johnny's still new here.
现在 浆糊脑子 你有没有打电话给冰鬼订灵车
Now, Porridge Head, did you call a hearse for the Gremlinbergs?
没有 你在看你的脸书页面 又在看
No, you're checking your Facebook page. Again.
德古拉 我跟大家说了 社交媒体
Drac, I told the guys social media
是推广旅馆的最好方式
is the best way to promote the hotel.
对吧 克利夫顿
Right, Clifton?
所以 德古拉 我想说一下我作为你
So, Drac, I wanted to go through some thoughts I had,
新任的人类关系协调助理的一些想法
as your new human relations coordinating co-assistant.
请说 毕竟这是份真正的工作
Sure. It's a real job.
而不是为了让梅维开心 你赖着不走的低廉借口
Not a cheap excuse to keep Mavis happy, so you never leave here.
没错 所以 我在想
Right. So, I was thinking,
既然我们都有这么多人类来这儿了 那或许可以更新一些配备
since we have so many humans now, maybe update some of the acts?
比如 或许换一下魔术师
Like, maybe the magician?
三只眼哈利有什么不好
What's wrong with Harry Three-Eye?
对于人类来说 他可能有点老派
Well, he might be a little old-school for the humans.
告诉我 先生 你的牌是什么
Tell me, sir, what was your card?
黑桃三
The three of spades?
这是你的牌吗 我的朋友
Is this your card, my friend?
哇哦
Whoa!
不行 哈利很棒
No, Harry's great.
不能把观众不嗨怪在哈利头上
Can't blame Harry for the crowd not being hip.
好吧 那韦恩呢
Okay, what about Wayne?
韦恩 你是疯了吗 他是我的兄弟
Wayne? Are you nuts? He's my boy.
那能换个活儿给他吗 不要网球可以吗
Then maybe something other than tennis?
好了 你要做的就是
Okay, so, what you wanna do
球来的时候举起拍子
is lift the racket right on impact,
然后就能打出一手好球了
so you get that nice top spin.
试试打一个吧
Try and hit one.
什么东西 什么声音 是从我身上发出来的
What is that? What's the noise? It's on me!
是我给你买的手机响了而已
It's just the cell phone I got you.
克利夫顿在给你发短信
Clifton's sending you a
好让你能练习下怎么回短信
text so you can practice how to write back.
什么东 这破手机不听使唤
What the... It's not doing it.
我来
I got it.
现在你可以给克利夫顿发短信了
Now you can text Clifton.
好吧好吧
All right, fine.
你是怎么做到的
How do you do this?
或许是你的指甲的问题
Maybe it's your fingernails.
很简单的 看 我给梅维丝发条短信
It's easy. Look. I'll text Mavis.
今晚要约会了 好激动啊
Psyched for date night.
看见么 看 她立马就回我了
See? And now look, she texted right back.
“取消吧 我离不开丹尼斯”
Gotta cancel. Can't leave Dennis.
好吧
Okay.
我们再也不能独处了吗
Are we never allowed to be alone again?
我也需要被爱啊
I need to feel loved, too.
然后发送
And send.
够了 我只学会一件事 你真窝囊
Okay. All that taught me is that you're pathetic.
嗯 知道了 或许你就用蓝牙
Yeah, got it. Maybe you should just get Bluetooth.
没问题 蓝牙 过来
Okay. Blue Tooth, come over here.
然后呢
So, now what?
该起床啦 我的丹尼索维奇
Rise and shine, my Denisovich.
嗨 外公
Hi, Papa.
你好啊 我的小恶魔 你做了个香甜的噩梦吗
Hello, my little devil. Did you have sweet nightmares?
嗯哼 我梦见了一条剑龙
Uh-huh. I dreamed that I saw a stegosaurus.
噢 然后你在喝他的血吗
Oh... And were you drinking his blood?
没有
No.
那不管他了
Just throwing it out there.
嘿 想不想做些很酷的事
Hey! You want to do something cool?
想
Yeah!
我来教你怎样变成蝙蝠 像我一样
I'm going to teach you how to turn into a bat. Like me.
-看见没 -好酷
- See? - Cool.
没错 很酷 我就说了
Yes! Cool, like I said.
现在你试试
Now you try.
我是只蝙蝠
I'm a bat.
我是只蝙蝠 我是只蝙蝠 我是只蝙蝠
I'm a bat. I'm a bat. I'm a bat.
我是只蝙蝠
I'm a bat.
我的意思是 一只真正的蝙蝠
I mean, a real bat.
我是只蝙蝠
I'm a bat!
丹尼索维奇 深呼吸 你真的可以变成蝙蝠的
Denisovich. Take a breath. You can really turn into a bat.
试试 找到蝙蝠的感觉
Try. Feel the bat.
不是只小鸡
Not a chicken.
那是什么 机械舞吗
What's that? The electric boogaloo?
我要是跳段舞给你看 你能试着飞一下吗
If I show you I can bust a move, will you try to fly, then?
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
爸爸 你们怎么在跳舞
Dad? Why are you guys dancing?
呃 他在梦舞
Uh, he was sleep-dancing.
过来 小甜心 回床上睡觉吧
Come on, sweetie. Back to bed.
“回床上睡觉吧” 已经过了晚上八点了
Back to bed? It's already after 8:00 p.M.
你不记得新的作息表了吗
Don't you remember the new sleep schedule?
他要去上半天的人类课堂
He's going to human classes half the day.
今晚他要是能睡到凌晨两点的话
If he could just sleep till 2:00 A.M.
对他来说就太好了
Tonight, it'd be so great for him.
但是 宝贝小死神 韦恩的六条小狼犬
But, honeydeath, six of Wayne's wolf pups
今晚要开生日派对啊
are having a birthday party tonight.
你不会忍心让他错过吧
You wouldn't want him to miss that.
爸爸 我爱那些小狼犬
Dad, I love the wolf pups,
但是他们对于丹尼斯来说 有些太粗暴了
but they're a little too rough for Dennis.
“太粗暴”
Too rough?
你没注意到吗 丹尼斯不一样
Haven't you noticed? Dennis is different.
你在说什么 丹尼索维奇不该与怪兽为伍吗
What are you saying? Denisovich shouldn't be around monsters?
-我爱怪兽 动画片 动画片 -哈
I love monsters! Video! Video! Ha!
噢 你是想要让德古拉外公看看你的怪兽动画片吗
Oh, you wanna show Papa Drac your monster video?
没错
Yeah!
谁是最酷的怪兽
Who's the coolest monster?
蛋糕糕
Kakie!
蛋糕糕是一只快乐的怪兽
Wee! Kakie one happy monster!
蛋糕糕爱吃蛋糕 好吃
Kakie love cake! Yummy!
汤米肚子痛了
Tummy get a tummyache.
哇哦 哇哦 哇哦 那根本不是只怪兽
Whoa, whoa, whoa. How is that a monster?
吃点蛋糕吧 唔兹拉帕巴姆
Have some cake, Wuzzlelumplebum.
记住了 孩子们 真正的怪兽喜欢分享
Remember, kids, a real monster always shares.
“分享”没错 我一想到怪兽的时候就会想到“分享”
Shares? Yes! When I think monsters, I think "Shares."
现在 让我来告诉你什么才是真正的怪兽 丹尼索维奇
Now, let me tell you what a real monster is, Denisovich.
爸爸 别这样 他才五岁啊 别逼他
Dad, please. He's practically five already. Don't force it.
慢慢来 唔兹拉帕巴姆
Slow down, Wuzzlelumplebum.
一闪一闪小星星 究竟何物
# Twinkle, twinkle, little star How I wonder #
妈咪 我已经过了听摇篮曲的年龄了
Mommy, I'm too old for lullabies.
什么 摇篮曲不是那样唱的
What? That's not how that one goes.
大多数人都这样唱
This is the way most people sing it.
“大多数人” 我的版本又怎么了
Most people? What's wrong with...
受苦 受难 痛苦中尖叫
# Suffer, suffer, scream in pain #
鲜血从你脑中溢
# Blood is spilling from your brain #
-爸爸 -得了吧 你知道我就是这样唱给你听的
Daddy. Come on. You know how I sang it to you.
僵尸咬你像葡干
# Zombies gnaw you like a plum #
撕成碎片你完蛋
# Piercing cries and you succumb #
受苦 受难 痛苦中尖叫
# Suffer, suffer, scream in pain #
然后你就死翘翘
# You will never breathe again #
还是有用的嘛
Still works.
生日快乐 沃利 维尔森
Happy birthday, Wally, Wilson,
伍皮 伟伦 维皮还有韦恩
Whoopi, Waylon, Weepy and Wanye.
丹尼索维奇 好孩子 你来了
Denisovich! My big boy! You made it!
我仔细想了下你所说的 爸爸
I thought about what you said, Dad.
或许我有点保护过度了
Maybe I was being a little overprotective.
谢谢你 棺材蛋糕小甜心
Thank you, coffin cake.
丹尼斯 我爱你 噌
Dennis! I love you! Zing!
嗨 温妮
Hi, Winnie.
我真的好爱你的美味草莓锁 噌 噌
I just love your yummy strawberry locks! Zing, zing!
温妮 别老缠着丹尼斯 亲爱的 抱歉 梅维丝
Winnie. Give him his space, hon. I'm sorry, Mavis.
没事的 旺达阿姨 他们只是在闹着玩
It's okay, Aunt Wanda. They're just playing.
噢 天呐 地狱边境吗 我之前爱死那游戏了
Holy rabies! Limbo? I used to love that game!
去玩啊 梅维
Get in there, Mavey.
真的吗 但是我现在为人母了啊
Really? But I'm a parent now.
给他们看看是怎么玩
Show 'em how it's done.
好的 好的 好的
Okay. Okay, okay.
不是吧 一个皮纳塔
No way! A pinata?
噢 梅维丝 亲爱的 那个稍后再玩
Oh, Mavis, honey. That's for later.
我们不想小狼犬们吃太多的
We don't want the pups to have too much...
糖果
Candy!
糖
Sugar.
对不起 是我引起的吗
I'm sorry. Did I start all that?
别担心 幼崽们就是这样闹腾
Don't worry. There's a reason they call it a litter.
丹尼斯 你还好吗
Dennis! Are you okay?
我抢到一颗糖
I got a candy.
看 你掉了颗牙
Look! Your tooth came out.
不是吧 他的牙磕掉了吗
Are you kidding me? He got his tooth knocked out?
噢 是的 没错 要长出尖牙啦
Oh, yes, indeed. Here comes the fang.
爸爸 他的乳齿都不是尖牙 这颗怎么会是呢
Dad. His baby tooth wasn't a fang. Why would this one be?
他不是个怪物
He's not a monster.
太阳就要出来了 我们得送他去上课了
The sun's gonna come out soon, and we gotta get to his classes.
我们这的课程有什么不好吗 比如说儿童瑜伽
What's wrong with the classes we have here? Like the kids' yoga?
瑜伽
Yoga!
这儿是丹尼索维奇的家
This is Denisovich's home.
我不知道 爸爸
I don't know, Dad.
你不知道什么
What don't you know?
嗯 我们在想要不要搬家
Well, we've been talking about moving.
搬到对于丹尼斯来说更安全的地方去
Somewhere safer for Dennis.
或许搬到加利福尼亚 强尼长大的地方去
Maybe where Johnny grew up in California.
对不起 但是你不能
I'm sorry, but you can't
强迫别人变成自身以外的东西
just make somebody something they're not.
过来 亲爱的 我们得走了
Come on, honey. We have to go.
噌 噌
Zing, zing?
梅维 等等 你不是认真的吧
Mavey, wait. You can't mean that.
这事儿你有份吗 要搬家
You're in on this? The leaving?
呃 都还不确定
Uh... It's not definite at all.
她只是在说说而已
It's just something she's definitely talking about,
但在我们搬走之前 都还不确定
but until we do it, it's not definitized.
他是用鸟饵把我埋起来了吗
Did he just cover me with birdseed?
没错 他把我埋起来了
Yeah, he covered me.
爸爸 这不是尖牙
Dad, it's not a fang.
爸爸 我不知道这里是否是丹尼斯的好居所
Dad, I don't know if it's the right place for Dennis.
对吧 强尼
Right, Johnny?
噢 嘿 老家伙 不是我 是梅维
Oh, hey, dudeman. It's not me. It's Mavey.
嘿 老家伙 我胆小怕事
Hey, dudeman. I'm afraid to say anything.
嘿 老家伙 我是个老家伙
Hey, dudeman. I'm a dudeman!
呃 德古拉 你在和谁说话
Uh, Drac? Who you talkin' to?
别来打扰 伯爵现在很不满
Do not disturb. The count's wiggin' out in here.
德古拉 你在不满些什么
What are you wiggin' out about, Drac?
孩子们 梅维说她想要搬家
The kids. Mavey Wavey's saying she wants to leave.
她想要搬家 强尼怎么说 他不想走啊
She wants to leave? What about Johnny? He doesn't wanna go.
他为了丹尼斯把旅馆变得更有人味啊
He's making the hotel more human-y for Dennis.
你懂的 因为他不是个怪物
You know, seeing that he isn't a monster.
他是个怪物
He is a monster!
他只不过是晚长牙而已
He's just a late fanger.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
那我可以成为个手模
And I could be a hand model.
闭嘴 都是那些人类的破事
Shut up! It's all that human-y stuff
困扰了可怜的丹尼索维奇
that's confusing poor Denisovich.
所以或许你可以让丹尼索维奇身处在更多的怪兽事儿里
So maybe you gotta get the kid around more monster-y things. Ooh!
噢 我需要件斗篷
Oh, I need a cape.
不行啊 梅维丝总是在周围监督着我
I can't. She's always around, checking up on me.
老兄 要是你有些独处的时间就好了
Man, if you could just get some alone time.
等会 那也是强尼想要的
Wait a minute. That's what Johnny wants, too.
和梅维丝独处
Alone time with Mavis.
在他们结婚前
Have they even had a vacation
他们度过假吗
since before they were married?
他们现在要去了 还有我们 弗兰克 你真是个天才
They're going to now. And so are we. Frank, you're a genius.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
我们要带着丹尼索维奇去所有我们常去的地方
We'll take Denisovich to all our old haunts.
每个人都展示给他看我们的技能
Each of us will show him our skills.
教会他如何做一个怪物
Teach him how to be a monster.
然后他很快就会长出尖牙的
And he'll be fanging it up in no time.
小家伙下周就五岁了
Boy turns five next week.
到他生日那天要是还不能成为吸血鬼的话 就再也不可能了
If he's not a vampire by his birthday, it ain't happenin'.
噢 不会那样的 宝贝
Oh, it ain't ain't happening, baby.
他所需要的就是与他的吸血公独处
All he needs is time with his vampa.
“吸血公”
Vampa?
吸血鬼外公
Vampire grandpa.
不是吧 老兄 很明显的好吧
Come on, man. That's obvious.
强尼 出来一下
Johnny. Come outside.
什么 谁在外面
What? Who is it?
是你岳父 我们谈谈
It's your father-in-law. I need to talk to you.
怎么了
What's up?
先让我赶开他们 抱歉
Let me get rid of them. Sorry.
没关系 我有在试着集中注意力
No problem-o. I was kinda diggin' the attention.
他俩能待着吗 我觉得他俩还没准备好离开
Can they stay? I don't think they're ready to leave yet.
去去去 找你的妈妈去
Come on. Go to your mother.
听着 你想留在这儿 是吗
Look, you want to stay here, right?
当然
Of course.
这是第一个我能真正做我自己的地方
This is the first place where I can really be myself.
自从他们发明了芝心匹萨后
I haven't felt this alive
我从未感到如此有活力
since they invented stuffed-crust pizza.
嗯 那 我们得做些事情 我的计划是这样的
Well, then, we've got some work to do. Okay, so here's the plan.
或许带她回你的家乡是个好主意
Maybe it's a good idea to take her to your hometown.
但是记住
But remember...
嗯 要给他吃牛油果切片 杏仁燕麦片
So, it's sliced avocado, rolled oats with apricot,
每次洗完澡都要记得擦上艾维诺润肤霜
the Aveeno moisturizer after every bath.
然后在他皮肤粘膜色素沉着之前在他屁股上擦上牛油树脂
And then the shea butter on his tush before his PJs
然后在我给他念自然拼读教材的时候
and then 20 minutes with the nebulizer
用二十分钟的喷雾器
while I read his Learning Factory Phonics book to him.
带小孩很麻烦的 爸爸 我们可以带上丹尼斯的
It's asking a lot, Dad. We could just take Dennis with us.
什么 逗我呢 然后打破他的日常生活习惯吗
What? Are you kidding me? And get him off his routine?
不不不
No, no, no.
你们去加利福尼亚吧
You kids go to California,
去看看那里是否是养育丹尼索维奇的好地方
and see if it's the right place to raise Denisovich.
你记得怎么视频通话吧
And you remember how to video chat?
记得记得 用手机然后按键然后就是折磨
Yes, yes. With the phone and the buttons and the agony.
谢谢你如此善解人意
Thanks for being so understanding,
爸爸 我知道你会保护他平平安安的
Dad. I know you'll keep him safe.
当然了 梅维 相信我 即使木桩插心我都誓死保护他
Of course, Mavey. Stake my heart and hope to die.
我只是会很想他
I'm just gonna miss him so much.
我爱你 丹尼斯
I love you, Dennis.
我爱你 妈咪
I love you, Mommy.
我会每晚给他讲睡前吸血鬼故事的
I'll tell him Mavey Wavey stories every night before bed.
你最棒了 我爱你 爸爸
You're the best. I love you, Dad.
我会想你们所有人的 你们都是我的家人
Gonna miss all you guys. You're all my family.
爱你 德古拉
Love you, Drac.
嗯 我也爱你
Yes. I love you, too.
记得我们的计划 让她分心然后高兴就好
Now, remember the plan. Just keep her distracted and happy.
-但是不要太高兴了 明白吗 -明白
But not too happy, capisce? Got it.
执行行动“让她分心然后高兴就好”
Operation "Just Keep Her Distracted and Happy,
“但是不要太高兴了 明白吗” 立即开始 没错吧
But Not Too Happy, Capisce, Starts now. Cool?
表面要笑嘻嘻的
Smiling on the outside.
你会拥抱我的背包吗
Will you hug my backpack?
不
No.
回床上睡觉吧
Back to bed.
啊 是 我们要上床睡觉了 我们都爱床
Ah, yes, we'll get to the bed. We all love the bed.
但是我们要先做一件事
But we're just gonna do one thing first.
我们要去的地方天气热吗
Is it shorts weather where we're going?
天 希望不是 我的身材还没恢复到可以穿泳衣
Jeez. I hope not. My body isn't swimsuit-ready yet.
随便 格里芬在哪
Whatever. Where's Griffin?
嘿 能等会吗 我想和艾米丽告别
Hey, can I have a second? I'm just saying goodbye to Emily.
噢 兄弟
Oh, brother.
我会非常想你的
I'm gonna miss you so much.
坚强点 亲爱的
You know, you have to be strong, honey.
因为我们间的感情坚如磐石
Because what we have is unbreakable.
宝贝 别哭了 大家都在看呢
Babe, don't cry. Everyone's looking.
好吧 我跟他好好学学这个
Okay, I gotta call him on this.
就让他演完吧 早完早散场
Just let him play it out, get it over with.
好了 你们这对鸳鸯
Okay, you two lovebirds.
喝你的香槟然后走吧
Drink your champagne and let's get going.
噢 是 当然 好的
Oh, yeah. No, sure. Okay.
干杯 宝贝
Cheers, babe.
噢 你这个笨蛋
Oh. You klutz.
我们就不能说说吗
We can't say nothin' about this?
不行 我们没时间磨蹭了
No. We don't have time for zingers.
这该死的安全带是怎么系上的
How do you click in the stupid car seat?
老兄 剪剪指甲吧
You gotta cut those nails, man.
我们都只是用胶带绑着我们的孩子
We just strap our kids down with duct tape.
他在这干嘛
What's he doing here?
我跟他说他可以来 他从没出过旅馆
I told him he could come. He's never been outside the hotel.
布拉比 没位置了 不好意思 老兄
Blobby, there's no room. Sorry, man.
嗯 不是吧
Yeah, that ain't happenin'.
好吧 把他安置在调皮鬼摩托车上 走吧
Fine, put him on the Rascal. Let's just get going.
我们去哪儿啊 德古拉外公
Where are we going, Papa Drac?
噢 丹尼索维奇 我们去冒险
Oh, Denisovich, we're going to have an adventure.
一场怪物冒险之旅
A monster-y adventure.
耶 怪物 我们去吃蛋糕
Yay! Monsters! We're gonna eat cake.
他刚说什么
What did he say?
不 这次怪物之旅没有蛋糕
No. No cake on this monster trip.
没有蛋糕 因为蛋糕糕说“吃太多蛋糕会肚子痛”
No cake, cebause Kakie says, "Too much cake makes tummy ache."
耶
Yay!
“怪物喜欢分享”
A monster always shares.
哇哦
Wow!
看来要不止一周了
We may need more than a week.
嘿 你知道谁能快速治好小孩吗 弗拉德
Hey, you know who could fix the kid in a snap? Vlad.
什么 我们不需要叫弗拉德 我们自有办法
What? We don't need to call Vlad. We got this.
看见没 丹尼索维奇 怪物们都很和善 和你一样
You see, Denisovich, monsters are nice, just like you.
但是月亮一出来 真正的怪物活动就开始了
But when the moon comes out, the real monster fun begins.
很可怕 对吧 伙计们
Being scary. Right, guys?
伙计们 伙计们 你们有什么毛病
Guys? Guys! What is wrong with you?
别这样 人人都爱那首歌
Come on. Everybody likes that song.
我们不是普通人 我们是可怕的怪物 记得吗
We're not everybody. We're scary monsters. Remember?
嘿 你在放什么
Hey, what are you putting in?
是本电子书
It's an audio book.
大脚怪的人生故事 自动播放的
Bigfoot's life story. He reads it himself.
第一章
Chapter One.
这次旅行肯定棒呆了
This is gonna be so amazing.
噢 没错 你会很高兴的 但不会太高兴
Oh, yeah. You're gonna be so happy, but not too happy.
-哈 -什么
Huh? What?
我想看你成长过程中做的每件事
I wanna see everything you did growing up.
只要你分心了 明白吗
As long as you're distracted, capisce?
我们在拜访我父母的路上可以参观一些景点
We can hit a few spots on the way to my parents.
让我给家里打个电话
Lemme just quickly call home.
啊 别打
Ah! Don't do that.
那里才凌晨一点 丹尼斯还没起床呢
It's only 1:00 A.M. There. Dennis isn't even up yet.
没错 我只是还不习惯离开他
Right. I'm just not used to being away from him.
没事的 你爸爸都能搞定
Everything's gonna be cool. Your dad was so all over it.
我知道 他最棒了
I know. He's the best.
右拐 这里
Right turn, here.
丹尼索维奇 该起床啦
Denisovich, rise and shine.
伙计们，这让你们想起了什么
Boys, this bringing back any memories?
我们一百岁的时候还曾经在这里徘徊
We used to prowl around here when we were in our 100s.
斯洛博齐亚的黑暗森林
The Dark Forest of Slobozia.
他们建成这样挺漂亮的
Nice how they built it up.
好吧 下车
Okay, out of the car.
丹尼索维奇 你将会看到
Denisovich, you're going to see
每一个怪物各显身手
every monster do his specialty.
首先 弗兰克会让我们知道 他是怎么吓人的
First, Frank's gonna show us how he scares people.
耶 他会说 吓死你
Yay! He's gonna say, "Boo."
是的 但是我不认为这样吓人每次都有用
Yeah, I don't think "Boos" Ever work.
但是这就是为什么我们现在来到这里 来向大师学习
But that's why we're here. To learn from the master.
好 我先露一手
Okay, I'll give it a shot.
是的 我猜测这取决于工作
Yeah, guess it just depends on work.
科学怪人
Frankenstein!
嘿 你们好吗
Hey, how ya doin'?
你好帅啊 我们能和你照一张相吗 可以吗
You're awesome! Can we take a picture? Is that okay?
当然没问题 不就是个小自拍嘛
Sure, okay. Little selfie action.
不是吧
For real?
太酷了 谢谢你
Awesome! Thank you so much.
嘿 祝你们过得愉快
Hey, have a great day.
吓死你
Boo!
哦 他好可爱啊 好可爱啊
Oh. He's adorable. He's adorable.
是挺可爱的 没错
Adorable, yes.
虽然不吓人 但好歹是个开始
Not scary, but "Boo" Is a start.
我生日蛋糕上将会有最酷的人
My birthday cake's gonna have the coolest guy on it.
让我猜猜 蛋糕糕
Let me guess. Kakie.
不是他 他真的很酷 穿着斗篷 在墙壁间穿梭
No. He's so cool. He climbs walls and wears a cape.
哦是吗 那这个很酷的人是谁呢
Oh, really. And who is this very cool guy?
蝙蝠侠
Batman!
蝙蝠侠 很好
Batman. Great.
你不知道另外一个带斗篷的人也很酷吗
You don't know anyone else with a cape that's cool?
这里不错 停车
This is good. Stop here.
好了 韦恩 到你了 快去杀些什么
Okay, Wayne. It's your turn. Go kill something.
丹尼索维奇 看好了哦
Denisovich, watch this.
什么
What?
我告诉过你了 快去
I told you, come on.
如果我们不激励他
If we don't inspire Denisovich,
他怎么能找到他内心的怪物本质呢
how's he going to find his inner monster?
谁有怪物本质
Who's in a monster?
没有 只是
Nobody, just...
给 吃个牛油果吧
Here, have an avocado.
耶
Yay!
你妈妈说这个的脂肪很好
Your mommy says it's a good fat.
谁知道那是什么意思
Whatever the heaven that means.
听着 我不会再变成怪物
Listen, I'm not gonna set monsters back again
就为了让你的孙子变成吸血鬼那样
just to make your grandkid like vampires.
无论如何 这里不会有人被杀 一切都
Anyway, there's nothing to kill here. It's all been...
多么可爱啊
What a cutie.
但是杀了他
But kill him.
很好 你知道我好多年没干这种事了
Oh, great. You know I haven't done this in years.
我们不需要再杀人了 我们有馅饼吃
We don't need to kill anymore. We have Pop-Tarts.
你会喜欢的 丹尼索维奇
Denisovich, you're going to love this.
韦恩要吃下那整只鹿 然后下一只就是你的
Wayne's going to eat that whole deer, and the next one's yours.
韦恩 上
Wayne, go.
哦 拜托 我已经老到猎不动鹿了
Oh, man. I'm too old for this.
好吧 该怎么做来着
Okay, how's it go again?
不 不 等等 这是月圆的时候该干的
No, no, wait. That's for the moon.
哦 我咆哮 对 开始了
Oh, I growl. Right, here goes.
咆哮
Growl!
接住这个飞盘 伙计
Get it, boy.
接住它 韦恩叔叔
Get it, Uncle Wayne.
某狼人 你真的咆哮了吗
Some werewolf. Did you actually say the word "Growl?"
你这个没用鬼
You're a werewussy.
我就说我已经生锈了
I said I was rusty.
把飞盘给我
Gimme me that Frisbee.
不要 这是我的飞盘 我抢来的
No! It's my Frisbee! I fetched it!
给我 给我
Give it to me! Give it back!
拿来 给我 快给我
Give it over here! Give me that! Give it back!
他没事的 他是软波比呢
He's fine. He's Blobby.
这个地方是如此的美丽动人
This place is so amazing and scenic.
你想先给我看什么
What do you wanna show me first?
嗯 我不知道
Mmm. I don't know.
这很漂亮 但天黑之后
It's pretty, but there's really
真的没什么可做的
nothing to do once it gets dark.
等等 那是什么地方
Wait. What's that place?
你是说 我可以在这些
So, you're telling me that I can pick
各种口味的薯片里面随便挑吗
between all these different kinds of chips?
是的
Yes.
大家要怎么选啊
How do people decide?
那个美丽的红宝石喷泉是什么
Now what's that beautiful fountain of rubies?
强尼 你喝过这种思冰乐吗
Johnny, have you tried this Slurpee?
别喝那么急 亲爱的
Not that quickly, hon.
它有四十八种口味 我们全都得尝尝
It comes in 48 flavors. We have to try them all.
呃 我不知道我们有没有时间
Uh, I don't know if we have time.
为什么 这个地方不是一整夜都开着的 对吧 先生
Why? This place is open all night. Right, sir?
是的
Yes.
强尼 看
Johnny, look.
他们正在拍这个地方的电视节目 我们就是明星
They're making a TV show about this place and we're the stars.
全世界好啊
Hello, world.
真棒
Awesome.
真是棒极了 你真幸运 卡尔
It's totally awesome. You're so lucky, Kal.
全世界好啊
Hello, world.
好吧 墨瑞 该你了
Okay, Murray. Your turn.
不好意思 你知道这附近哪里有卖吃的吗[直译是 能被咬一口]
Excuse us. Do you know where someone can get a bite around here?
你真的在问一只吸血鬼什么地方能让人被咬一口吗
Did you seriously just ask a vampire where to get a bite?
哦 天哪 我不是这个意思 我们不是这附近的人
Oh, gosh. I didn't mean... We're not from around here.
真的太尴尬了 开车啦
This is so embarrassing. Just keep going.
不好意思打扰你 超爱你的巧克力麦片哦
Sorry to bother you. Love your chocolate cereal.
你想让我做什么
So, what do you want me to do now?
丹尼索沃奇 你不会相信的
Denisovich, you won't believe it.
木乃伊能穿墙而过
The mummy can crash through walls
也可以变成一群甲壳虫
and turn into a swarm of beetles
还能对所有人施咒
and put a curse on anyone.
听起来好恶劣啊
That sounds mean.
但恶劣得很有趣 好的
It's fun mean. Okay.
快看看
So, check it out.
墨瑞要召唤
Murray's going to conjure
一场你从未见过的超级大沙尘暴
up the biggest sandstorm you've ever seen.
开始
Hit it!
沙尘暴 好久没召唤过了
Sandstorm? It's been awhile.
那我不管 快点 念你的小咒语
Not my problem. Do it. Say your little spell.
好吧
Okay.
我可以的 弗兰克 韦恩 格里芬 不要被吓晕哦
I got this. Frank, Wayne, Griffin, just try not to faint.
我的背
My back.
噢 等等
Oh. Wait.
多可爱啊
How cute!
等一等 在游乐场那里停 看看那些可爱的孩子
Wait. Stop at that playground. Look at these cute kids.
天呐 这看起来太酷爆了
Holy rabies! This looks like a blast.
我不知道 梅维
I don't know, Mavey.
如果你不知道自己在干什么的话 这可能会很危险
This can be pretty dangerous if you don't know what you're doing.
当然 我当然会骑了
Of course, I rock these bikes.
我能试试吗 小家伙
May I, little dude?
小心 噢耶
Check it out. Oh, yeah.
我每个夏天都这么骑着玩的
This is how I rolled every summer.
我想我把车子弄坏了
I think I scratched it.
轮到我
My turn.
梅维斯 我告诉你 我花了好几年才练成这样
Mavey, I told you, it took me years to get this good.
既然如此 我试试吧
Well, I'll give it a try.
瞧见没有 这是我的女朋友 手下败将们
You feel me now? That's my girlfriend, suckers.
你的老婆 强尼
Your wife, Johnny.
我老婆 更厉害了
My wife. Even better.
这太棒了 你这技术是在哪里学的
That was sick, lady. Where did you learn how to do that stuff?
特兰西瓦尼亚
Transylvania.
太酷了 我有一个来自宾夕法尼亚的表姐
That's cool. I have a cousin from Pennsylvania.
噢 这些小家伙们太可爱了 丹尼斯会喜欢他们的
Oh. These little guys are so sweet. Dennis would love them.
这真是个抚养孩子的好地方
What an awesome place to raise a kid.
噢 抚养一个孩子
Oh. To raise a kid?
我不知道好在哪里了
I don't know about awesome.
可能是好极了 明白吗
Maybe tubular. Capisce?
总之 我们该去我父母家了
Anyways, we should hit my folks' place.
我说这时候我们应该到那里了
I said we'd be there by now.
当然
Sure.
噢 嗨 现在特兰西瓦尼亚已经过了三点了
Oh, hey, it's after 3:00 o'clock in Transylvania.
我要检查一下丹尼斯的情况，好吗
I'm gonna check on Dennis, okay?
巧克力麦片 你在开玩笑吗
Chocolate cereal. Are you kidding me?
别紧张 德古拉 那是因为他们喜欢我们
It's okay, Drac. It's 'cause they love us.
好吧 怪物就是这样的
Yeah. Monsters are what's goin' on.
好吧 你应该就像我一样敞开胸怀接受
Oh, yeah. You should embrace it like I did.
我都发行一张畅销的锻炼视频了
I've got a best-selling workout video.
跟着我做 女士们 向右 再向左
Follow me, ladies. Right. And left.
不 姑娘们 看着我 你们没在看
No, girls. Watch me. You're not watching.
我们继续 八 七 六
Here we go. And eight and seven and six...
伙计们 那可不是我
That's not me, guys.
得了吧 即使是大脚
Come on, even Bigfoot's
也席卷了德国足球联赛
tearin' it up in the German soccer league.
哦不 哦 不 不  不
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no.
是梅维斯打来的
It's Mavis.
你得接电话
You gotta answer it.
你按得太用力了，轻点
You're pushin' too hard. Lighter.
好吧
All right!
丹尼斯 醒醒 噢 他睡死了
Denisovich, wake up. Oh, boy, he's out cold.
我来搞定
I got this.
爸爸 怎么这么久才接电话
Dad, what took so long?
什么
What?
没什么 梅维  我们大家在旅馆都很好
Nothing, Mavey. We're all great here at the hotel.
就在忙旅馆的事情
Just doing hotel things.
抱歉，你不能控制一下你的呼吸吗
Sorry, can't handle your breath.
我知道了
I hear ya.
你怎么样
How are you?
我们玩得非常高兴
We're having a blast.
我们刚刚去骑了单车还去了小商场 这里太好玩了
We just went biking and mini-marting. It's so fun here.
丹尼斯还好吗
Is Dennis okay?
噢 当然了
Oh. Of course.
你想看看他吗
You want to see him?
是 是的
Yes. Yes, I do.
嗨 宝贝 你过得怎么样
Hi, baby. How are you?
妈咪
Mommy.
我很开心
I happy.
嘿 小家伙
Hey, little dude.
他为什么戴着墨镜
Why is he wearing sunglasses?
我们正在玩游戏
Oh, we were playing.
超级英雄的游戏
It's a superhero thing.
因为 我是墨镜侠 我要拯救世界
Cebause, I'm Sunglasses Man, to the rescue!
好吧 把他放下来吧 我正飞呢
Okay, take it down a notch. I'm flying.
你声音有些奇怪
You sound funny.
噢不不 那就是他墨镜侠版的声音
Oh, no, no, that's his Sunglasses Man voice.
有静电干扰 信号很差 梅维斯 你听得到吗
Static. The signal is bad. Mavis, are you there?
对 我还
Yeah, I'm still...
好吧 我想他玩的很开心
All right. I guess he's having fun.
他当然开心了
Of course he is.
哇 我用墨镜侠解决了问题
Wow, I nailed it with the Sunglasses Man.
就在我的头顶
Right off the top of my head.
我仍出了[因喂]这个词 大家都瞧见了吗
I threw in a "Cebause." Did everyone see that?
她说她很开心 强尼把任务搞砸了
She said she was having fun. Johnny's blowing it.
她骑了自行车和逛了小商场 她要搬走了
She's biking and mini-marting. She's gonna wanna move!
我要好好矫正这个孩子 我们要到了没有
I gotta fix this kid now. Are we almost there or what?
好吧 我可能
Okay, I may
在几英里之前 拐错了弯
have taken a wrong turn a few miles back.
别生气 什么
Don't get mad. What?
来人把这个导航器开一下
Someone turn on the navigator on this thing.
看看我触碰得多轻
Look how light I touch it.
请输入你的目的地
Please enter your destination.
拜托 我求你了
Please. I am begging you.
会没事的 丹尼索维奇
Yeah, this is gonna be good, Denisovich.
那可怕的本质 就在你的血液之中 好吗
Scary stuff, okay? It's in you.
我们只需要集中精力吓人就好了
We just gotta concentrate on the scary.
德古拉外公 你会想念外婆吗
Papa Drac? Do you miss Grandma?
想念外婆 当然 我会啊
Miss Grandma? Oh. Sure, I do.
我每天都想念她 她是我的爱
I miss her every day. She was my zing.
你为什么要问这个
Why do you ask?
我不知道
I don't know.
你想念谁了吗
Do you miss anybody?
我想我的妈妈和爸爸
I miss Mommy and Daddy.
还有谁呢 你想念温妮吗
And who else? You miss that Winnie?
那个扑倒你 一直想要舔你的小家伙
The pup who tackles you and tries to lick you all the time?
想啊 但是我们只是朋友
Yeah, but we're just friends.
哦 不 不 不 你是德古拉家的人
Oh, no, no, no. You're a Dracula.
你不会只和温妮那样可爱 毛茸茸的小家伙做朋友的
You can't just be friends with a cute, hairy number like Winnie.
-立刻右转 -这里转 你个笨蛋
Right turn, now! Here. You imbecile!
哦 对哦 快转 格里芬
Oh, right. Turn, Griffin!
遵命 德古拉外公
Yes, Papa Drac.
等着瞧 伙计们
Wait and see, fellas.
这孩子会立刻狂饮山羊血
This kid'll be guzzling goat blood in no time.
已经到达目的地 好耶
- You have arrived at your destination. - Yes!
好的 我们到了
Yes! Here we are.
这是我还是个孩子的时候 来过的吸血鬼夏令营
It's the vampire summer camp I went to as a kid.
叫什么名字 吸血营吗
What's it, Camp Vamp?
不是 谁会把自己的夏令营命名为 吸血营
No. Who names their camp "Camp Vamp?"
这是维尼帕卡卡夏令营
It's Camp Winnepacaca.
你看看 丹尼索维奇
You see, Denisovich?
我就在这里学会捕捉老鼠和变身的
This is where I learned to catch mice and shapeshift.
并用学会使用我难以置信的力量和勇气 很酷吧
And use my incredible powers and strength. It's pretty cool. Huh?
羽毛球
Badminton.
是啊 我不记得有这个羽毛球
Yes, I don't remember this badminting.
哦 就是今晚吗 你们好啊
Well, well, is this a night? How ya doin', folks?
我是达纳主任
I'm Dana, the director.
我们非常高兴你们这些传奇人物来访
We're sure excited to have you legends visitin' us.
我能为你做什么
What can I do you for?
我非常感兴趣
Well, I'm very interested
送我的孙子 丹尼索维奇 来这里
in sending my grandboy, Denisovich, here.
哦 就是这个一头红发 没有尖牙的小家伙吗
Oh. This little redheaded, non-fangy little guy?
哦 尖牙还没有长出来而已 他晚长牙
Oh, they're in there. He's a late fanger.
这也是我们来到这里的原因
That's why we came here.
你能给我们展示一些实操演练吗
Can you show us some of the drills,
比如像他们抓老鼠的地方
like where they catch the mice?
可以 当然现在我们叫它通鼠窜
Can do. A-course now we call it Tee-Mousing.
所以他们不必去抓老鼠了吗
So they don't have to catch the mice?
不用 我们发现这个办法可以很好地建立他们的信心
Nope. We find this is a good way to build their confidence.
快来这里
Come here.
就在那里 你是怎么回事
It's right there! What's the matter with you?
变个法子而已
Hokey-pokey.
就是那儿 丹尼索维奇 外公就在那里学会飞的
There it is, Denisovich. Where Papa learned to fly.
噢 我也想像你一样飞
Ooh! I wanna fly like Papa.
对 但现在我们都在这边进行了
Yeah. We're over here, now.
保险起见 不得不减低规模
Had to scale it down. Insurance.
救我 救我 救我
Help me. Help me. Help me.
变个法子而已 一会篝火边见
Hokey-pokey. See ya at the campfire.
哦天哪 欢迎你们
Well, gosh! Welcome, you two.
嘿 大家好
Hey, gang.
嗨 大家好 这真是太令人兴奋了
Hi, guys. This is so exciting.
啊 看看这一切 真酷
Ah! Look at all of this. So cool.
哇 不敢相信我居然在这里
Wow! I can't believe I'm actually here.
你已经在这里了
Well, you are.
现在怎么样了 你是彻夜不眠 然后白天睡觉吗
Now, how does it work? Are you up all night and sleep all day?
是啊
Yeah.
你们想要我做什么都行
Oh. I'll do whatever you guys want.
很好
Good.
因为我给你买了漂亮的太阳帽 琳达
'Cause I bought this pretty sunhat for you. Linda.
但是这雨披 如果你想要安全
But otherwise this poncho, if you wanna be safe.
这事我们可以稍后处理 琳达
We can deal with it later, Linda.
好吧
Okay.
噢 过来看看
Oh! Come see.
我装饰了你的卧室
I've set up your bedroom.
这就像特兰西瓦尼亚一样
It's just like Transylvania.
噢 特兰西瓦尼亚 那是一次有趣的经历
Oh, Transylvania. That was a fun experience.
麦克害怕他会被开膛破肚 被吃掉
Mike was afraid he'd get disemboweled and eaten,
但是我告诉他 他真傻
but I told him he was just being silly.
那是你 琳达
That was you, Linda.
噢 他们来了
Oh. There they are.
这小区有一个人类和怪物组合的家庭
You know, we have a couple of mixed families in the neighborhood,
所以我想着请他们过来
so I thought I'd invite them over.
既然你们想要搬来这里
They might be nice for you guys to talk to
那跟他们聊一聊可能有好处
since you're thinkin' about moving here.
嗨 卡伦 嗨 潘若歌拉
Hi, Caren. Hi, Pandragora.
欢迎你 梅维斯 嗨 你们好
Welcome, Mavis. Hey, guys.
是的 你们可以好好在这儿生活的 一点儿也别担心
Yeah, you're gonna dig it here. Don't even worry.
人们对于我们选择的生活方式完全没有异议
People are totally cool with our lifestyle choice.
我是说 孩子们有时会被欺负
I mean, the kids get picked on a little,
但是这会让他们更加强大
but it toughens them up.
噢 嗨 你们好 这是洛瑞塔
Oh, hey, you guys. And this is Loretta.
她嫁给了保罗 他是一个狼人
She's married to Paul, who's a werewolf.
什么
Excuse me?
是的 我刚正跟梅维斯介绍
Yes, I was telling Mavis
镇上其他人类与怪物结合的夫妻
about the other monster-human couples in town.
我不是狼人
I am not a werewolf.
噢 我还以为
Oh. I thought...
好吧 欢迎你留下来品尝一些纸杯蛋糕
Well, you're welcome to stay and have some cupcakes.
#吸血鬼永远是朋友#
# Vampires will be friends forever #
#世世纪纪永远都会在一起#
# Through the centuries together #
#即使在阳光最灿烂的日子里#
# Even in the brightest sunny weather #
#吸血鬼永远是朋友#
# Vampires will be friends forever #
#真的朋友#
# Literally #
#直至永远#
# Forever #
干得漂亮 吸血鬼们 给你们自己一个拥抱
Great job, vampires. Give yourselves a hug.
我们走
We're going.
什么 去哪
What? Where?
为什么我们要这样子
Why are we doing this?
难道你更愿意听那些恶心的新歌吗
You'd rather be listening to those putrid new songs?
[迈克尔划着船载你的尸体上岸]和
What happened to Michael Row Your Corpse Ashore?
[老狼麦克手里握着斧头]都不唱了吗
Or Old McWerewolf Had An Axe?
我们不该到这上面来的 德古拉
We shouldn't be up here, Drac.
谁准备好飞行了吗
Who's ready to fly?
我 我 像个超级英雄一样地飞
Me! Me! Like a superhero.
要更好的 要像个吸血鬼一样
Better! Like a vampire!
这塔摇摇欲坠
This thing is rickety.
你知道吗 也许这孩子不该飞
You know what? Maybe the kid isn't supposed to fly.
给我闭嘴 这就是他们学习的过程
Quiet. This is how they learn.
你把他们扔出去然后他们自己就学会了
You throw them and they figure it out.
我就是这么学会的
It's how I was taught.
我现在就要飞
I wanna fly now!
小乖蝙蝠 如果你需要外公的话 外公就在这儿保护你
Attabat. You know Papa's right here if you need him.
呃 无法直视
Uh. I can't watch this.
别这样
Please don't.
我们飞啦
Here we go!
他还是没飞
He's still not flying.
他会的
He will.
还没有
Still not.
马上就会了
It'll happen.
这塔真的好高
This is a tall tower.
这样才好
That's why it's good.
你应该去接他
You should get him.
他会摔得粉身碎骨的
He's gonna fall to his death.
他在慢慢学习中
He's taking his time.
德古拉
Drac!
我第一次也是如此
I did that my first time.
他离地太近了
He's getting too close to the ground!
你知道吗 也许他不会飞了
You know what? He's not gonna fly.
我说过了 外公会一直在这儿保护你
I told you. Papa's always here for you.
再来 再来
Again! Again!
噢亲爱的 哦 恶魔 我们必须报告这事
Oh, dear. Oh, my devil. We're gonna have to report this.
你是说上报纸吗
You mean to the papers?
我觉得那会很酷 但是我还不想登报
I guess it was pretty cool, but I'm not about getting press.
不 先生 我是指报给当地政府
No, sir. I mean the authorities.
我必须上报 置儿童于危险罪
I can't not report child endangerment.
喔 听我说 那很有好玩
Whoa! Listen to me. That was fun.
你的歌才是置儿童于危险之中
Your singing is child endangerment.
我们应该下去帮他吗
Should we go down and help him?
绝不 我告诉过他这有多疯狂 他自作自受
Nope. I told him this was nuts. He's on his own.
我们应该给这男孩的妈妈打电话
We have to call the boy's mother.
不 不会打的
No, that ain't happening.
他妈妈已经是个精神错乱的颠颠了
His mother's already nutsy koo koo!
我必须按章办事
I have to follow protocol.
你不会按章办事的
You will not follow protocol.
我是一个吸血鬼 我不会被催眠的
I'm a vampire. I can't be hypnotized.
对哦
Right.
现在 请你合作 别逼我报警
Now, please. Don't make me call the police.
没人会报告任何人
No one's calling nobody!
着火了
Fire!
停住 倒地然后翻滚 停住 倒地然后翻滚
Stop, drop and roll. Stop, drop and roll.
尖叫没有用
Screaming's not helping!
呀
Yay!
我们是坏人吗 德古拉外公
Are we bad guys, Papa Drac?
坏人
Bad?
不 你是世上最好的孩子
No. You're the best kid in the world.
不是我们点火的 是塔楼的问题
We didn't start the fire. It was the tower.
那是个非常危险的塔楼
That's a very unsafe tower.
你应该庆幸我们没有报警
You're lucky we don't call the authorities.
走吧 我的英雄
Let's go, my hero.
因为我是蝙蝠侠 快上我的蝙蝠战车
Cebause I'm Batman! To the Batmobile!
是 快上
Yes. To the...
我很抱歉发生了那一切 我猜他们还以为你会喜欢
Sorry about all that stuff. I guess they thought you'd like it.
为什么我在这里如此怪异
Why do I feel so weird here?
不 宝贝 他们才是奇怪的人
No, hon. They're being weird.
我想他们只是想帮我
I think they're just trying to help me.
我是说 我从小在那旅馆长大 对外界一无所知
I mean, I grew up knowing nothing living inside that hotel.
而你在圣诞老人这里长大 无所不知
And you learned about everything growing up in Santa Claus.
是圣克鲁兹 但是 呃
Santa Cruz. But, uh...
如果让丹尼斯在精灵旅社外面长大
Maybe if Dennis grows up away from Transylvania,
他就不会那么怪异 不会像我一样
he won't be so freaky. Like me.
你疯了吗 梅维斯 你很棒的
Are you nuts? Mavis, you're a blast.
你那么地充满活力 对所有事都感到好奇
You're so full of life and curious about everything.
如果丹尼斯能长成像你一样
If Dennis grows up to be just like you,
我将是世界上最幸运的爸爸
I'll be the luckiest dad in the world.
我爱你 强尼斯顿
I love you, Johnnystein.
你知道吗
You know what?
只要我们相伴永久 在哪儿都会快乐的
As long as we're all together, we'll be happy anywhere.
即使在精灵旅社
Even at the hotel.
是的
Yes!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
看看我朋友发给我的这个视频
Check out this video my friend sent me.
这孩子是个超赞的不怕死星人
This kid is an awesome daredevil.
哦 老兄
Oh, dude!
你看到了吗
Did you get it?
等等 那是丹尼斯吗
Wait! Is that Dennis?
不 是吗 不 很难看清楚 但是
- No! Is it? No. It's just hard to see. - But...
哦 刚删了它 所以 没有了
Oops. Just deleted it. So, it's gone.
什么 是梅维斯 我不会接的
What? It's Mavis. I'm not answering it.
快接 德古拉 你一定得接
Come on, Drac. You have to.
好吧
All right!
你好 甜心
Yes, honeybunch.
爸 你在哪里
Dad? Where are you?
呃 我们在旅社外面露天烧烤呢
Um... We're outside the hotel having a little cookout.
百分百安全
It's perfectly safe.
那是什么声音 警笛吗
What's that noise? Is that a siren?
哦 那只是一些爱啼哭的妖怪来住店了
Oh, those are just some wailing banshees checking in.
安静点 你们这些妖怪
Quiet, you banshees.
我们正举办一个百分百安全的篝火晚会
We're trying to have a perfectly safe cookout over here.
妈妈 我要打招呼 妈妈 妈妈
Mommy! I wanna say hi! Mommy! Mommy!
德古拉爷爷刚刚正教我怎么飞
Papa Drac just tried to teach me how to fly.
等等 那是他妈妈吗
Wait a minute. Is that the mother?
哦 不好 又卡住了
Oh, no. Static again.
我现在就回旅社
I am coming back to the hotel right now.
你最好给我在那里不然我发誓
And you better be there or I swear,
爸爸 你会非常抱歉的
Dad, you're gonna be very sorry.
怎么了
What's goin' on?
我们必须马上回家
We need to get home right away.
好的 我去拿一下我的背包
Okay. I'll go wake up my backpack.
伙计们 我们得走了
Guys, we gotta move.
我们没有车 怎么离开这儿
We got no car! How we gonna get out of here?
别担心 我打过电话了
Don't worry. I made a call.
对不起 兄弟 我们本打算早点打给你的
I'm sorry, Blobby. We really meant to call you sooner.
快开
Hit it!
去特兰西瓦尼亚
Transylvania.
你想去哪里
You want to go where?
特兰西瓦尼亚 越快越好
Transylvania. As soon as possible.
没有直达特兰西瓦尼亚的飞机
We don't fly direct to Transylvania.
没有吗
You don't?
你可以先去布加勒斯特 但你必须
You can go to Bucharest, but you'll have to
在芝加哥转机 然后到苏黎世
switch planes in Chicago and then Zurich.
那么 什么时候会到
So, when would we get there?
芝加哥的航班因天气问题延误了
Well, the Chicago flight's delayed due to bad weather.
所以 两张经济舱票吗
So, two seats in coach?
不要
No!
-不会吧 -是的
- No! - Yes.
你非要现在去吗 在我们终于没有堵车的时候
You have to go now? When we finally have no traffic.
你要杀死我吗 兄弟
You're killing me, Blobby.
我头上还有点云 要自拍一下
I still have some cloud on me. Gotta do a selfie!
强尼 现在不行
Johnny! Not now!
好吧 待会再说
Okay. Maybe later.
这踏板车快没油了 我们到不了了
This scooter thing's out of juice. We're never gonna make it.
弗兰克 吹气
Frank, blow.
就是现在
Now!
多有意思呀 你笑什么呢 你喜欢吗
How fun is this? Why are you laughing? You like that?
看这个
Watch this.
麻利麻利麻利哄
Coochie-coochie-coochie-coo!
这就是飞翔 丹尼索维奇
Now this is flying, Denisovich.
像一个吸血鬼一样
Like a vampire.
哇
Wee!
这才是我的乖孩子 看你飞得多好
That's my boy. Look at you go.
你是穿披风里面最帅的人 德拉克外公
You're the coolest guy who wears a cape, Papa Drac.
哇哦
Ugh!
那么 嗨 你们什么时候能到
So, hey, when are you going to get here already?
我们已经等了
We've been waiting...
把儿子给我
Give me my son.
我们只是去吃了些牛油果
We just went out for some avocados.
妈妈 我飞了
Mommy! I flew!
我看到了
I saw.
#妈妈是一个精神错乱的颠颠#
# Mother's already nutsy koo koo #
#精神错乱的颠颠#
# Nutsy koo koo #
#颠颠 噢 亲爱的 噢 亲爱的#
- # Koo koo # - COUNSELOR: Oh, dear. Oh, dear
#噢 我的小恶魔 我必须按章办事#
# Oh, my devil I have to follow protocol #
#不会发生的 不会发生的#
# That ain't happening That ain't happening #
#妈妈已经#
# Mother's already #
#颠颠#
# Koo koo #
我本担心丹尼斯待在别的怪物身边不安全
I was worried Dennis wasn't safe around other monsters.
现在我觉得他待在你身边也不安全
Now I don't even feel like he's safe around you.
但我刚只是
But I was just...
你之前说了什么
What was it you said?
人也好 怪物也罢 独角兽都行 都没有关系
Human, monster, unicorn. That it didn't matter?
好吧 我只是知道他的生活会
Well, I just know his life would...
星期三我们会在这里举办他的生日派对
We'll have his birthday party here on Wednesday.
然后我们就搬走
Then we're moving.
求你了 梅维 别走
Please, Mavey. Don't leave.
或许你已经让人类进入你的旅馆 爸爸
Maybe you've let humans into your hotel, Dad.
但我认为你从没让他们进入你内心
But I don't think you've let them into your heart.
我可以的 我可以的
I can do it. I can do it.
我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠
I'm a bat. I'm a bat.
我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠
I'm a bat. I'm a bat. I'm a bat!
丹尼斯 你在干什么呢 小甜心
Dennis? What are you doing, sweetie?
呃 没什么
Uh... Nothing.
小心 让我抱你下来
Careful. Let me help you down from there.
你对你的大派对感到兴奋吗
Are you getting excited about your big party?
可能吧
I guess so.
你猜谁会来 爸爸全家人哦
You know who's coming? Daddy's whole family.
迈克爷爷和琳达奶奶
Grandpa Mike and Grandma Linda.
还有所有爱你的堂兄妹和叔叔阿姨
All your cousins and aunts and uncles who love you so much.
我们搬去加州时他们会跟我们一起哦
And then they're gonna be with us when we move to California.
妈妈 我们搬走是因为我不是怪物吗
Mommy, are we going away cebause I'm not a monster?
什么 不是的 丹尼斯 当然不是
What? No. Dennis, of course not.
这只是成长必须经历的事情
It's just grown-up stuff.
好吧 但是德古拉外公怎么办
Okay. But what about Papa Drac?
他要一人住在这里了
He's gonna be here all alone.
德古拉外公必须留下来经营旅馆
Papa Drac has to stay here to run the hotel.
但他会来看我们 我们也会来看他
But he'll visit us. And we'll visit him.
我们可以每晚给他打电话吗
Can we call him every night?
当然可以
Sure.
太好了
Awesome!
你好 我们来了
Hello. We're here.
#强尼的家人到来之夜#
# The night brings Johnny's family here #
#夺走德古拉所有心爱之物#
# To take away all that Drac holds dear #
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome, welcome.
#隐藏你的内心#
# Hide your feelings #
#把所有情绪藏起#
# Keep them all inside #
老兄 你干嘛想搬走 这地方简直不可思议
Dude, why do you wanna leave? This place is out of control.
我可不想走
I don't wanna leave.
这里有这些超酷的僵尸怪兽
All these awesome freakazoids!
那么 哪个是最酷的怪物
So, who's the coolest monster?
蛋糕糕
Kakie.
蛋糕糕 真窝囊
Kakie. What a wussbag.
全家聚会是不是很美好
Isn't it nice to have the whole family together?
梅维斯 你家里有什么堂兄妹亲戚的吗
Mavis, do you have any cousins or thingies in your family?
没有 只有我和我爸
No. It's just been me and Dad.
我还不知道你妈妈怎么离开的
I never did ask how you lost your mom.
哦 她被愤怒的人类杀死了
Oh. She was killed by angry humans.
#尴尬#
# Awkward #
但是我有个爷爷 弗拉德
But there is my Grandpa Vlad.
哦 你有个爷爷
Oh, you have a grandpa?
是的 他会来派对的 我邀请了他
Yeah. He'll be at the party. I invited him.
你邀请了他？
You invited him?
爸 他从没见过丹尼斯
Dad, he's never seen Dennis.
我想离开前让他们见一面
I wanted them to meet once before we go.
当然 太好了 太赞了 好老人弗拉德
Sure. Great. Peachy. Good old Vlad.
谁有湿纸巾吗
Anybody have a wet wipe?
我的天啊 他终于邀请我了
Holy rabies. He finally invites me to something.
他有了外孙？
He's got a grandkid?
而他从未对你提过
And he never told you?
放松点 贝拉 至少家族里多了一个吸血鬼
Easy, Bela. At least there's another vampire in the family.
这是在一家旅馆 奢侈奢侈
It's at a hotel? Fancy schmancy.
旅馆是人类的
Hotels are for humans!
贝拉 闭上你的血盆大口 看看你都干了什么
Bela, shut your blood hole. Look what you started.
别担心 大家
Don't worry, gang.
我教育我的儿子要憎恨 杀戮 还有偷走人类的灵魂
I raised my son to hate and kill and steal the souls of humans
要做我的好孩子
like a good boy.
是的 弗拉德爷爷看到我和强尼策划的
Yes, Grandpa Vlad will be so happy
这个盛大的化妆舞会 会非常开心的
when he sees the big masquerade party Johnny and I have planned.
什么
What?
好好配合 那是我的爸爸
Play along. It's my dad.
你有爸爸？真有趣
You have a dad? That's funny.
听我说 不能让我爸知道你或者是
Listen to me. My dad cannot know you're a human.
你的家人是人类
Or any of your family.
什么 但是 德古拉 我很自豪我们是
What? But, Drac, I'm proud that we're...
否则他会偷走你家人的灵魂然后吃了你的背包
Or he'll steal your family's souls and eat your backpack.
对了 大家
That's right, gang.
我们要把生日宴会搞成化妆舞会
We're gonna make the birthday a monster masquerade party.
真的？那真有趣
Really? Oh, that's lovely.
就好像在丹尼斯成为正常人
Sort of like a last hurrah
之前最后一次的狂欢
before Dennis gets to be with normal people.
没有更好的说法了
I couldn't have said it better.
你觉得怎么样 梅维斯
What do you think, Mavis?
我想我已经喜欢上变得很怪异了
I think I'm starting to like being creepy.
你该庆幸我们没有报警
You're lucky we don't call the authorities.
走吧 我的英雄
Let's go, my hero.
因为我是蝙蝠侠
Cebause I'm Batman!
好 去我的蝙蝠战车
Yes! To the Batmobile!
你的屁股被一个女孩踢了 蝙蝠侠
Got your butt kicked by a girl, Batman.
是 没关系 我不会哭的
Yeah. Whatever. I'm not about to cry.
精灵旅社
Hotel Transylvania.
我闻到了人类的味道
I smell humans!
把它砸了
Tear it down!
贝拉 我们在外面 你当然会闻到人类气息
Bela, we're in the outside world. You're gonna smell humans.
你知道吗 你就在外面等我好了 这是家庭聚会
You know what? Just wait outside for me. This is family stuff.
你会碍手碍脚的
You'll only get in the way.
我只是想看看小曾孙
I just wanna meet the little fanger.
他应该认识一下他伟大的吸血鬼曾祖父
He should know his great-vampa.
他的什么
His what?
吸血鬼曾祖父 得了吧 多明显的事
Vampire grandpa. Come on. That was obvious.
超赞的派对
Amazing party!
那么 你觉得如何
So, what do you think?
这就是你的吸血鬼打扮 你是什么 疯子吗
This is your vampire costume? What are you, nuts?
我上网买的
I ordered it online.
只有那家店可以第二天送到
It was the only place that delivered overnight.
你头上好像装了个狒狒的屁股
You look like you got a baboon's butt on your head.
你练习过说话方式吗
Have you at least practiced your voice?
你可不能像嬉皮士一样说话
You can't just talk like a hippie.
我不是嬉皮士 我是个懒鬼
I'm not a hippie. I'm a slacker.
像吸血鬼一样说话
Talk like a vampire.
吾名为强尼 我是个吸血鬼
My name is Count Jonafang. I am a vampire.
好吧 吸血鬼不会到处说 “我是个吸血鬼”
Okay, vampires don't go around saying, "I am a vampire."
对不起 吾是强尼 给我血 血 血
Sorry. I am Count Jonafang. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me?
对不起 我太紧张了
I'm sorry. I'm nervous.
好吧 听着 如果你认为我都不会喜欢
Yeah, listen, if you think I don't like it,
那你绝对不要
you definitely don't want to say,
冲着我父亲喊 给我血 血 血
Bleh, bleh-bleh, In front of my father.
先生 蛋糕糕大师来了
Sir, Master Kakie has arrived.
噢 嘿
Oh, hey.
德拉科 这是布兰登 外号 蛋糕糕
Drac, this is Brandon, a.K.A. Kakie.
我们请他来给丹尼斯表演的 嘿 伙计
We got him for Dennis. Hey, man.
很不高兴认识你
Nauseated to meet you.
宴会什么时候开始 半小时后我有场图书展销会
When does this happen? I got a book fair in half an hour.
好了 我的吸血鬼儿子呢
All right. Where's my vampson?
噢 得了吧 还是得搞个这么戏剧化的开场嘛
Oh, please. Still has to make a dramatic entrance.
老爸 看看你
Dad! Look at you!
所以你现在是在经营一家旅馆吗
So you run a hotel now?
从黑暗王子堕落到房间服务之王
From Prince of Darkness to King of Room Service.
是啊 很高兴见到你
Yes. So good to see you.
我马上来陪你
I'll be right with you.
让弗拉德远离人类和梅维斯
Keep Vlad away from the humans and Mavis.
我马上去做
I'm on it.
噢 这可真是件漂亮的戏服
Oh, now that is a neat costume.
这两位闻起来真奇怪
These two smell funny.
噢 你是个欧洲人
Oh, you're European.
这叫做除臭剂
It's called deodorant.
没人这么取笑整个大陆的 琳达
Nothing like insulting an entire continent, Linda.
嘿 伯爵 最近怎么样啊 我是弗兰肯斯坦
Hey, Count! How goes it? Frankenstein.
事实上 严格来说我是弗兰肯斯坦的怪物
Actually, I'm technically Frankenstein's monster.
弗兰肯斯坦 他是那个博士
Frankenstein, he's the doctor who...
我很愿意继续听 打电话跟我的人预约吧
Would love to hear more. Call my people.
那么 让我给你介绍下你儿子的其他朋友
So, let me introduce you to some of your son's other buddies.
这是墨瑞
This is Murray.
请不要杀了我
Please don't kill me!
我是说 哟 小弗 你好啊
I mean, yo, V! What's up?
会讲话的厕纸 呵呵 这可是个新朋友
Talking toilet paper. Well, that's a new one.
好了 那孩子在哪儿 他才是我想见的
All right! Where's the kid? That's who I wanna meet.
强尼
Johnny!
这是德古拉的女婿
This is Dracula's son-in-law.
我是强纳梵伯爵
I am Count Jonafang.
呵 嘿 黑羊
Bleh, bleh, black sheep.
你身上有羊毛吗
Have you any wool?
你头上是什么玩意儿
What's that thing on your head?
看起来像是我奶奶的奶子
Looks like my grandmother's boobies.
爸爸 那个长得奇怪的人是谁呀
Daddy, who's the man with the funny face?
就是这个孩子
Is this the kid?
就是他
It sure is.
让我看看他的尖牙
Let me see those fangs.
你在干什么
What are you doin'?
噢 我只是太爱他了
Oh, I just love him so much.
我想抱抱他的小尖牙
I want to hug him right in the fangs that he has.
我再说一遍 让我看看他的尖牙
I repeat, lemme see those fangs.
噢 他长牙比较慢 就像你一样
Oh, he's a late fanger, just like you.
是的 是的 就像我一样
Yes. Yes. Just like me.
这位大人物以前可是个小爱哭鬼呢
The big shot here was a little crybaby, all right.
是的 是的 我是
Yes, yes, I was.
以前还会尿床
Used to pee in his bed.
好了 爸爸
Okay, Dad.
我们只需要把那孩子的尖牙给吓出来
We just need to scare the fangs out of the kid.
吓出来？
Hare ha hangs?
是啊 这就是我对这位大块头做的事情
Yeah, it's what I did for Mr. Tough Guy here.
首先 你得拿到迟长牙的小家伙
First, you've got to possess something
觉得又甜蜜又天真的东西
the late fanger finds sweet and innocent.
然后你给他展示这玩意儿到底是什么 然后
Then you show them what's what and...
嘣
Pop!
相信我 这样会把尖牙吓出来的 对吧 德古拉
Trust me. It'll scare the fangs right out. Right, Drac?
讲真的 伙计们 如果我赶不上图书展销会
Seriously, guys, if I'm late for the book fair,
我会错过街头集市的
I'll miss the street fair.
那就是你要找的人
That's your guy.
附身吗 但是丹尼斯会很伤心的
Possessed? But Dennis will be so upset.
你还没明白吗 这是我们的机会
Don't you get it? This is our ticket.
如果这样对丹尼索维奇有用 嘣 他是个吸血鬼
If it works for Denisovich, boom! He's a vampire.
然后你们就都可以留下来了
And you all get to stay here.
好的 好的
All right. All right.
收到 很好
Capisce. Good call.
孩子们 所有人 坐下来
Kids, everyone, have a seat.
丹尼斯给你们准备了一个大惊喜
Dennis has a big surprise for you.
那就是绝无仅有的蛋糕糕 蛋糕怪物
The one and only Kakie, The Cake Monster!
嘿 孩子们 是我 蛋糕糕
Hey, kids! It's me, Kakie!
这是多么棒的蛋糕糕日呀
What a wonderful Kakie day it is!
现在 我有个问题 在场谁喜欢蛋糕呀
Now, I have a question. Who here loves cake?
上升
Rise!
为什么我飘起来了 能把舞台管理员找来吗
Why am I floating? Can I have the stage manager, please?
这我可不干啊
This isn't working for me.
害怕吗 丹尼索维奇 你感觉到什么了吗 什么变化
Scary, Denisovich? You feeling anything? Any change?
蛋糕糕还好吗
Is Kakie okay?
我要所有的蛋糕 只有懦夫才会分享
I want all the cake. Sharing is for cowards.
我可不记得这些电视里有放这片段
I don't remember any of this from the TV show.
唔 我大概在蓝光碟里看到过 彩蛋
Um... I think I saw it on a Blu-Ray disc, bonus stuff.
等等 为什么弗拉德爷爷会在那儿
Wait, why is Grandpa Vlad up there?
我害怕了 外公 蛋糕糕怎么了
I'm scared, Papa. What's happening to Kakie?
你不吃蛋糕 蛋糕就吃你
You don't eat cake. Cake eat you!
不
No!
停下来
Stop it!
-刚刚发生什么了 伙计 -我不干了
What just happened, man? I'm outta here.
没有任何家长会在尖叫网上给好评的
None of these parents better review this on Yelp.
嘿 你刚刚做什么了
Hey, what did you just do?
只要再多吓他一会
A few more seconds and
这孩子的尖牙就会冒出来了
the kid's fangs would have popped right out.
我不在乎 这根本不值得
I don't care. It's not worth it.
什么不值得
What's not worth it?
这是我想让小家伙变成吸血鬼的最后努力 这样你们就可以留下来了
It was my last attempt to make the boy a vampire, so you'd stay.
通过毁掉他最爱的东西吗 你怎么能这么做呢
By ruining his favorite thing? How could you do that?
我们实在没办法了
We were desperate.
你也搅和进来了
You were in on this?
丹尼斯在我的家乡不会开心的
Dennis won't be happy in my town.
丹尼斯根本就没去过那儿
Dennis hasn't been there.
#丈夫和妻子#
# Now husband and wife #
#感受到紧张和冲突#
# Feel the strain and the strife #
闭嘴
Shut up!
强尼 丹尼斯不是个怪物
Johnny, Dennis is not a monster.
他喜欢鳄梨
He likes avocado.
那是因为你都不让他吃其他好玩的东西
'Cause you don't let him eat anything fun.
我觉得丹尼斯只想做个正常的孩子
I think Dennis just wants to be normal.
我们能不能别用“正常”这个词了
Can we stop using the word "Normal"?
在我们的世界里 他就是正常的
Where we live now, he's normal.
他就是他 而且你不能强行改变他 爸爸
He is who he is. And you can't change him, Dad.
丹尼斯 你要去哪
Dennis, where are you going?
离开
Away.
但是你自己一个人出来不安全
But it's not safe out here by yourself.
我知道有个地方我们可以藏起来 跟我来
I know a place where we can hide. Follow me.
如果你不阻止我
If you didn't stop me,
我的曾孙就不用一辈子做个懦夫了
my great-grandson wouldn't have to be a wimp his whole life
就像那儿的邋遢鬼一样
like Schlumpy over here.
一个懦夫 强尼 冷静
A wimp? Johnny, be cool.
你想被扔出去吗 老家伙
You wanna throw down, old man?
1997年官方认证的黄带
Certified yellow belt since 1997.
不
No!
这是怎么回事 你不是个吸血鬼
What's this now? You're not a vampire?
血
Bleh?
他当然是个人类 他是我们的儿子 你以为我们是怪物吗
Of course he's human. He's our son. You think we're monsters?
你 你让你女儿嫁给了一个人类 还生了个人类小孩
You! You let your daughter marry a human and have a human kid?
你为什么不干脆拿根木桩戳我的心脏算了
Why don't you just put a stake through my heart.
我们不再恨人类了 他们也不恨我们
We don't hate humans anymore, and they don't hate us.
人类
Humans?
你就是个蠢蛋
You're a fool.
你的曾孙是我见过的最可爱最善良
Your great-grandson is the sweetest, kindest,
最特别的小男孩
most special boy I've ever met.
如果你仅仅因为他是半个人类
And if you can't give him the love
就不肯给他他应得的爱
he deserves because he's half-human,
那么你才是个蠢蛋
then you're the fool.
噢 爸爸
Oh, Daddy.
丹尼斯去哪儿了 丹尼斯
Hey, where is Dennis? Dennis!
丹尼斯
Dennis?
生日快乐 丹尼斯 我为你准备了一顿晚餐
Happy birthday, Dennis. I made you a treat.
死鸽子 快吃吧
Dead pigeon? Enjoy it.
因为当我从商学院毕业
'Cause once I graduate
并且开始自己经营公司之后
business school and start running a company,
你就再也吃不到这样自家做的饭菜了
you're not gonna get home-cooked meals like this anymore.
我必须搬走 维尼 去加利福尼亚
I have to move away, Winnie. To California.
我妈咪认为我在这儿不快乐
My mommy thinks I'm not happy here
因为我没有像你一样脸上长毛
cebause I don't have hair on my face like you.
很抱歉我不是个怪物
I'm sorry I'm not a monster.
不 你很完美 你是我知道的最好的男孩
No, you are perfect. You're the nicest boy I know.
而我有三百个兄弟
And I have 300 brothers.
你也很好 温妮
You're nice, too, Winnie.
哈 哈 哈 小小人类和他的宠物
Well, well, well. The little human and his pet.
丹尼斯 丹尼索维奇
Dennis! Denisovich!
他不在房间里
He's not in the room.
他不在水池边
He's not by the pool.
他不在这罐汤里
He's not in this pot of soup.
他能去哪儿呢
Where could he be?
我不知道我当初为什么要邀请你
I don't know why I ever invited you.
丹尼斯 丹尼斯
Dennis! Dennis!
丹尼索维奇
Denisovich!
丹尼斯
Dennis!
别挣扎了
Stop squirming.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
因为这是错的
Because this is wrong.
为什么每个人都不明白呢
Why doesn't anybody get that?
人类和怪物不能在一起
Humans don't belong with monsters.
你才错了
You're wrong!
我没有
I am not!
我把你们抓了当人质
I am holding you hostage.
而且我和我的伙伴们
And me and my crew are
要把那间装满人类的旅馆撕成碎片
gonna tear that human-hugging hotel to shreds.
你做不到的
You can't.
真的吗 为什么呢
Really? Why not?
因为
Cebause...
因为 为什么
Cebause, why?
因为这会让德古拉外公很伤心的
Cebause it will make Papa Drac sad.
喔 伤心 那你要怎么办呢
Ooh... Sad. And what are you gonna do about it?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道你为什么不知道吗
You know why you don't know?
因为你只是个弱小的小男孩
Cebause you're just a weak little boy.
那是什么
What was that?
丹尼斯 我们来了
Dennis, we're coming.
你还好吗 温妮
Are you okay, Winnie?
是的 我的王子
Yes, my zing.
丹尼斯 他在那儿 就在那儿
Dennis! There he is, right there.
丹尼斯 宝贝
Dennis! Baby!
我的大男孩
My big boy!
丹尼斯 我们在找你呐
Dennis, we were lookin' for ya.
甜心
Sweetheart.
见到你我太高兴了
I'm so happy to see you.
他的坏朋友来了
There's his mean friends.
噢 那可就好玩儿啦
Oh... This'll be fun.
不是我吃的哦
I didn't do that.
你太厉害啦 丹尼斯
You rock, Dennis.
他是说 丹尼索维奇
He means Denisovich.
蛋糕糕规则
Kakie rules!
丹尼斯 我来了 呜哇
Dennis, I'm coming. Whoa...
我就知道那些练习会有作用的
I knew all that practice would pay off.
这就对了 你们最好有多远飞多远
That's right, you better fly away.
德古拉外公 我是个吸血鬼还是个超级英雄
Papa Drac, I'm a vampire and a superhero.
现在我很酷了吧
Am I cool now?
现在 丹尼斯 你一直都很酷
Now? Dennis, you were always cool.
人也好 怪物也罢 独角兽都行 不管你是什么 你都很完美
Human, vampire, unicorn, you're perfect no matter what.
但是 既然我是吸血鬼 那我们能留下来吗
But since I'm a vampire, can we stay here?
当然
Yes.
太好了 耶！
All right! Yeah!
好了
All right!
但你得知道
But you have to know,
我们每个假期都会来看望你的
we're going to visit you here every holiday.
好啊 好啊
That's fine. That's fine.
不许再靠近我或者我的家人一步
Don't ever come near me or my family again.
不
No!
老爸 你刚刚救了一个人类
Daddy, you just saved a human.
所有有关这男孩的
All this pressure about
尖牙什么时候能长出来的压力
when the boy's fangs were coming out.
谁在乎啊 我的几年前都出来了 看
Who cares? Mine came out years ago! Look.
好了 爸爸 趁我们还没吐 赶紧把你的牙放回去
Okay, Dad, put 'em back in before we all barf.
嘿 今天应该还是某人的生日吧
Hey! Isn't it still somebody's birthday?
让我听见你们唱起来
Let me hear you sing!
不是我吃的哦
I didn't do that.